verywell.com 2017-11-19

# Terms of Use and Policies

At Verywell, we take online privacy seriously and we respect the concerns of our community of users. In this policy we describe our privacy practices with regard to information we collect through Verywell.com and affiliated sites (the “Site”), to help you make informed decisions about how you share information when you visit or use the site.

### Understanding How Information Is Collected on Verywell

#### Information You May Choose to Provide to Us

We may collect information, including personally identifiable information, directly from you if you choose to provide that information. For example, you may provide us with your name and contact information (such as an email address), date of birth, or other details of that nature, when you sign up for our newsletters or participate in promotions or surveys on the Site.

You also may choose to provide personally identifiable information about yourself when you participate in forums or discussions on the Site. Please be aware that information you post in these forums may be viewed or captured by anyone who visits the Site, therefore you should avoid posting sensitive personal information that you would not want to be available to the public.

#### Information That Is Automatically Collected When You Visit Verywell

When you access the Site, we and our third-party partners may automatically collect certain information about your visit using tools such as cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies. The information collected automatically when you visit the Site may include your IP address, characteristics of your operating system, information about your browser and system settings, data about the computer or mobile device you use to access the Site, unique device identifiers, clickstream data (which shows the page-by-page path you take as you browse the Site), and other details that generally are not considered personally identifiable.

**Cookies** are small files that websites and other online services use to store information about users on the users’ own computers. This Site may use cookies (such as HTTP and HTML5 cookies and Flash cookies), as well as other types of local storage. For more information about cookies, you may visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). See the section below regarding Your choices to learn more about how you may limit or disable cookies on your computer. If you choose to disable cookies, that could affect certain features of the Site that use cookies to enhance their functionality.

To manage our automatic data collection, we may place tags (often referred to as “web beacons”) on pages on the Site or in emails we send to you. **Web beacons** are small files that link web pages to particular web servers and their cookies, and they may be used for a variety of purposes, such as counting the number of visitors to the Site, analyzing how users navigate around the Site, assessing how many emails that we send are actually opened and which articles or links are viewed by visitors.

We also use third-party web analytics services, such as Google Analytics, on the Site, to provide us with statistics and other information about visitors to the Site. [Click here to learn more about Google Analytics and how you may opt out.](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)

**“Do Not Track” Signals.** Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “do not track” signal to websites and online services you visit. At this time there is no consensus among industry participants as to the meaning of “do not track” in this context. Like many other websites, Verywell.com is not configured to respond to “do not track” signals from browsers. [Click here to learn more about "do not track" signals.](https://allaboutdnt.com/)

Finally, companies that provide certain third-party apps, tools, widgets, and plug-ins that may appear on the Site (for example, Facebook “Like” buttons), also may use automated means to collect information regarding your interactions with these features. This information collection is subject to the privacy policies or notices of those providers.

### How We May Use Information We Collect

We may use the information gathered on Verywell for various purposes, including the purposes listed below. For example, if you were to contact us with a question and provide your email address, we would use the email address you provided to respond to your inquiry. In addition, we use information we collect from you and through the Site to:

  * Provide products and services you request (such as when you sign up to receive our email newsletters);
  * Respond to requests, questions, and comments, and provide other types of user support;
  * Offer you products and services, or direct you to portions of this Site or other websites, that we believe may interest you;
  * Communicate about, and administer your participation in, events, programs, contests, and other offers or promotions;
  * Carry out, evaluate, and improve our business (which may include developing new features for the Site; analyzing and enhancing the user experience on the Site; assessing the effectiveness of our marketing and advertising; and managing our communications);
  * Perform data analytics regarding usage of the Site (including market and customer research, trend analysis, financial analysis, and anonymization of personal information);
  * Guard against, identify, and prevent fraud and other criminal activity, claims, and other liabilities; and
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements, law enforcement requests, and our company policies.

### How We May Share Information

Our agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers may have access to information we collect through the Site to carry out work on our behalf. Those parties are restricted from using personal information collected through the Site for purposes other than to provide the requested assistance. In addition, we may share information:

  * With our affiliates for internal business purposes;
  * If we are required to do so by law, regulation, or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena);
  * In response to requests from government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities;
  * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity;
  * With respect to analytics and statistical information, to inform advertisers about the nature of our user base;
  * In the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including a reorganization, dissolution, or liquidation); and
  * With your consent or at your discretion.

### Your Choices

**Unsubscribe from emails.** To unsubscribe from a particular newsletter, click the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of that email newsletter. If you would like to globally opt-out from ALL Verywell email campaigns please send an email to [optout@verywell.com](mailto:optout@verywell.com) with "Unsubscribe" in the subject line. When we send newsletters to subscribers we may allow advertisers or partners to include messages in those newsletters, or we may send dedicated newsletters on behalf of those advertisers or partners. We may disclose your opt-out choices to third parties so that they can honor your preferences in accordance with applicable laws.

**Blocking cookies.** Certain browsers may be configured to notify you when you receive cookies, or allow you to restrict or disable certain cookies. If you choose to disable cookies, however, that could affect certain features of the Site that use cookies to enhance their functionality.

**Disabling local shared objects (“Flash cookies”).** We may use other kinds of local storage that function similarly, but are stored in different parts of your computer from ordinary browser cookies. Your browser may allow you to disable its HTML5 local storage or delete information contained in its HTML5 local storage. [Click here](http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html) for details about deleting information contained in "local shared objects" or adjusting related preferences.

**Options concerning third-party ad networks.** For more information about third-party ad networks and services that use these technologies, you can visit [www.aboutads.info](http://aboutads.info/) and [click here](http://aboutads.info/choices) to opt out or to learn more about your options. You also may visit the [NAI's site for additional options](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) on how to opt out of interest-based advertising.

### How We Protect Personal Information

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful, or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure, or use. That said, it is not possible to guarantee the security of information transmitted online, and you assume some risk with regard to the security of information you provide through any website, including this Site.

### Links From Verywell to Other Websites

On this Site we may provide links to other websites that are controlled by third parties. Linked websites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review. We are not responsible for the content, usage terms, or privacy policies of websites that we do not own or control.

### Surveys and Quizzes

While you are visiting Verywell, you may have the opportunity to participate in surveys, quizzes, or other interactive features that request information about you and your opinions and preferences. Your participation in these features is entirely voluntary. If you do choose to participate, please be aware that these features may be operated by a third party that is not controlled by Verywell, and therefore the information you provide may be collected by the third party and subject to its privacy policy.

### Children’s Privacy

This Site is not designed or intended for use by children, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete any such information.

### Information for Users Outside the United States

If you are visiting Verywell from outside the United States, please be aware that information we collect through the Site will be transferred to and stored on our servers in the United States. By using this Site, you acknowledge and consent to the transfer and processing of your personal data in the United States as described in this online privacy policy. Please be aware that the data protection laws and regulations applicable to your personal data transferred to the United States may be different from the laws in your country of residence.

### Our Notice to California Residents

Subject to certain limits, under California law California residents may ask us to provide them with a list of the categories of personal information that we have disclosed to third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, as well as the identity of those third parties. California residents may contact us as specified in the How to Contact Us section below to make a request for this information. 

### How We’ll Inform You About Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may update this online privacy policy periodically to reflect changes to our privacy practices, such as how we collect or use personal information. We will post a prominent notice on the Verywell.com home page to notify you of significant changes to this policy, and we indicate at the top of the policy the date when it was most recently updated.

### How to Contact Us

If you have questions about this policy or about our privacy practices, you may contact us by emailing [privacy@verywell.com.](mailto:privacy@verywell.com)

If you are a California resident inquiring about your California privacy rights, please include “California privacy rights request” in the subject line of your email.

You may also write to:

1500 Broadway, 6th Floor   
New York, NY 10036
